Guide to the A. Page Browne, Jr. Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
A. Page Browne, Jr. Papers
1960-1974
MS 1740
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
The papers are comprised of reports, research material, memoranda, correspondence, and newspaper clippings created and compiled by A. Page Browne Jr. as he traveled and conducted business in Hungary, Poland, Yugoslavia, Romania, and the Soviet Union. The collection documents Browne's business affairs and his reflections on economic conditions in the eastern bloc countries during the 1960s.
Browne, Augustus Page, 1932-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of A. Page Browne, Jr., 1989.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
A. Page Browne, Jr. was born in Boston, Massachusetts on May 23, 1932. He received his B.S. from Yale University in 1955. He became Assistant Treasurer and later Assistant Vice President of the International Banking Department of the Bankers Trust Company. He specialized in foreign trade and was among the first bankers to travel to the Soviet bloc countries to promote economic ties with the United States. During his travels, Browne observed the economic conditions of the communist countries and worked to increase East-West trade by meeting with representatives from foreign and national banks of Yugoslavia, Romania and Poland.
Scope and Contents
The papers are comprised of reports, research material, memoranda, correspondence, and newspaper clippings created and compiled by A. Page Browne Jr. as he traveled and conducted business in Hungary, Poland, Yugoslavia, Romania, and the Soviet Union. The collection documents Browne's business affairs and his reflections on economic conditions in the eastern bloc countries during the 1960s.
International economic relations; Browne, Augustus Page, 1932-; Bankers Trust Company (New York, N.Y.)
- Inventory, 1960-1974
  Scope and Contents
  The collection is organized under two headings, the Banker's Trust Company and Country files. The Banker's Trust Company folders include correspondence and memoranda concerning Browne's travels to Eastern Europe. Country files consist of Browne's background research on general economic conditions of the Soviet bloc countries.
  - Bankers Trust Company
    - General, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Memoranda, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Country files
    - Hungary, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Poland, 1960-1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Romania, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Soviet Union
      - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Economic reports, 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Yugoslavia, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)